Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1675-1960; 27 boxes, 8.5 linear feet
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Oct. 9, 1913; 11x8-1/2; Richardson, Hester Dorsey, 1867-1933
    Baltimore, Md., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning C.W.Peale portraits.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Oct. 16, 1913; A.L.S. 2p. with invitation to join the Order of Colonial Lords of Manors in America, and rules for membership.; Richardson, Hester Dorsey, Mrs.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Nov. 14, 1913; A.L.S. 5p; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Nov. 17, 1913; A.L.S. 4p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Dec. 15, [1913]; A.L.S. 2p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace [W. Sellers], Dec. 29, [1913?]; 9-3/4x6-1/2; Peale, A. C. (Albert Charles), 1849-1914
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning the sale of C.W.Peale paintings.
  - Letter to Horace [W. Sellers, 1913?; 9-3/4x6-1/2; Peale, A. C. (Albert Charles), 1849-1914
    ]. A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Sale of C.W.Peale minatures.
  - Letter to Horace [W.] Sellers, Merion, Penna., [1913?]; 5-1/4x4-1/4; Richardson, Hester Dorsey, 1867-1933 (Box 24)
    Baltimore, Md., A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Wishes to purchase a portrait by C.W. Peale for the DAR.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Jan. 25, 1914; A.L.S. 4p.; Dandridge, N. L. (Box 25)
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Jan. 27, 1914; A.L.S. 3p.; Hayward, Elizabeth Bullitt, Mrs.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Feb. 17, 1914; Hayward, Elizabeth Bullitt, Mrs.
  - Letter to Albert [C. Peale], Feb. 19, 1914; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Possible sale of some C.W.Peale paintings.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Feb. 27, 1914; A.L.S. 3p. Offers names of paintings and sheet music for Horace Sellers' biography of Charles Willson Peale.; Corner, Thomas Cromwell, 1865-1938
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, March 7, 1914; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, March 9, 1914; A.L.S. 2p. with newspaper article on Washington's College "Maryland's Oldest College"; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to J. J. Jusserand, April 10, 1914; T.L. 5p.; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, April 13, 1914; T.L.S. 2p.; Jusserand, J. J., (Jean Jules), 1855-1932
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, June 17, 1914; A.L.S. 4p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Oct. 20, 1914; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Oct. 20, 1914; T.L.S. 1p.; Jusserand, J. J., (Jean Jules), 1855-1932
  - Memorandum for Horace Wells Sellers, Dec. 19, 1914; 1p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Jan. 2, 1915; 7x4-1/2; Cret, Paul Philippe, 1876-1945
    Note from old folder: "Provenance not known. Not purchased with Peale papers."
    A.L.S. 3p. In pencil. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning World War I experiences. Grateful for AIA thoughts.
  - Letter to Mrs.Thomas B. [Sarah Arndt Sletor] Morris, Hot Springs, Va., Sept. 28, 1915; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Morris, Roland S. (Roland Sletor), 1874-1945
    A.L.S. 15p. (see Peale papers) Is closing the house, preparatory to sailing. The legal case is the worst he ever saw. Family news. Presented by C.C.Sellers; Feb. 16, 1967.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, April 13, 1916; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, Penna., April 28, 1916; 11x8-1/2; Lockwood, George R.
    St. Louis, Mo., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Asks for ancestry of C.W.Peale. His son, Preston, is in England now.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Nov. 22, 1916; A.L.S. 2p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Nov. 26, 1916; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Note to "Dear Cousin" [Horace W. Sellers], Dec. 29, 1916; 2-1/4x3-1/4; Gamble, Angelica E.
    Tallahassee, Fla., A.N.S. 1p.on calling card. (see Peale papers.) Glad to hear from him and news of some relatives.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Jan. 9, 1917; T.L.S. 2p.; Jusserand, J. J., (Jean Jules), 1855-1932
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Feb. 3, 1917; A.L.S. 2p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, May 7, 1917; 9x5-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    This was originally located in: H. W. Sellers. The "Draisiana" or "predestrian hobby horse of 1819."
    Doylestown, A.L.S. 3p.(see Peale papers.) Gives directions and advises him to make his speech about 20 minutes.
  - Letter to Mrs. Colton, Feb. 4, 1918; 7-1/2x5-3/4; Losanitch, Helen
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for her interest in Serbia.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Feb. 27, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Lockwood, George R.
    Philadelphia, Penna., St. Louis, Mo., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Would like reprints on C.W.Peale. Family matters.
  - Letter to horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, May 11, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Lockwood, George R.
    St. Louis, Mo., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Asks questions concerning the "Darley engraving of Angelica Peale crowning Washington." Family news.
  - Letter to George R. Lockwood, May 14, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Has an engraving of Peale's stove in Independence Hall. Concerning the engraving of Washington and Angelica Peale. Family news.
  - Letter to George R. Lockwood, St. Louis, Mo., May 23, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Washington's entry into Philadelphia, 1789, and Angelica Peale's crowing of him.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, May 24, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Lockwood, George R.
    St. Louis, Mo., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale Papers.) Thanks for the publication of Peale. News of his family.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, May 25, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Lockwood, George R.
    St. Louis, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale Papers.) Thanks for his story of Angelica Peale crowning Washington.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, July 1, 1919; 10x7-3/4; Worthington, Hobart
    Baltimore, Md., A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning two portraits by James Peale.
  - Letter to Horace [W. Sellers], May 10, 1920; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, 1852-
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale Papers.) Concerning the sale of Millbanks.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Nov. 17, 1920; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace [Wells Sellers], Jan. 27, 1921; 5-1/2x4-1/4; Grimmer, Louisa Peale
    Chattanooga, Tenn., A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Forwards something by G.E.Sellers. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Horace [W. Sellers], May 21, 1921; 6-1/2x5-1/4; Grimmer, Louisa Peale
    Chattanoogan, Tenn., A.L.S.: Lui. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Describes her life. Forwards G.E.Sellers items. Refers to Charles C.Sellers.
  - Letter to Lui [Peale], May 23, 1921; "Cousin Emma"
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, July 21, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Jennings, Walter, 1858-1933
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.and enc.of 1p. (see Peale Papers.) Concerning "Washington" minatures which he attributes to C.W.Peale and encloses letter from Knoedler.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Aug. 16, 1921; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Aug. 30, 1921; 8x5; Pendleton, Alexander R.
    Winchester, Va., A.L.S. 8p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning family matters, especially their C.W.Peale relationship.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Sept. 9, 1921; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pendleton, Alexander R.
    Winchester, Va., A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning C.W.Peale portraits.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, May 12, 1922; A.L.S. 3p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, June 4, 1922; A.L.S. 2p.; Dandridge, N. L.
  - Letter to Horace [W.] Sellers, Philadelphia, July 26, 1922; 8x5; Gunn, Katharine Mifflin
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Wants a record of james Peale's minatures.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Ardmore, Penna., Aug. 17, 1922; 5-1/4x4; Gunn, Katharine Mifflin
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 2p.and envelope. (see Peale papers.) Thanks for his help and sends newspaper clipping (wanting).
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, 1922; 8x5; Gunn, Katharine Mifflin
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning a James Peale and a possible C.W.Peale minature.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Feb. 23, 1923; A.L.S. 1p.; Clarke, Thomas
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, Penna., April 24, 1923; 11x8-1/2; Seymour, Edmund Bayly, Jr.
    Philadelphia, Penna., Typed L.S. 2p.,end. (see Peale papers.) Asks if Rembrandt Peale might have painted his grandmother. other questions about possible C.W.Peale portraits.
  - Letter to Horace W. Sellers, Aug. 18, 1923; Gunn, Katharine Mifflin
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Oct. 17, 1924; 9-1/2x6; Noxon, Frank W.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Wishes to sell a painting once owned by Rembrandt Peale, who acquired it from Benjamin West.
  - Letter to Frank W. Noxon, Philadelphia, Oct. 27, 1924; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Peale Papers.) Concerning paintings owned by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, Feb. 4, 1925; 11x8-1/2; Peale, Rubens H.
    Schuylkill Haven, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Sending the Philadelphia Museum book for copying.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Feb. 21, 1926; 7x5-1/2; Brent, Hally Carrington
    Ruxton, Md., [answered] A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Questions as to certain C.W.Peale sketches and portraits.
  - Letter to Roland S. Morris, March 20, 1927; Mary,------
    Presented by C. C. Sellers, March 17, 1967
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Feb. 3, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Wall, A. J. (Alexander James), 1884-1944
    New York, Typed L.S. 2p. Concerning the De Peyster family. vol Vp.1
  - Letter to Thomas L. Montgomery, Jan. 17, 1929; 6-1/2x5; Peale, Augustin Runyon
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Wishes to sell painting by C.W.Peale. Enclosed originally in letter from T.L. Montgomery to H.W.Sellers; Jan.18,1929.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 18, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Montgomery, Thomas Lynch, 1862-
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Forwards letter of Mrs. A.R.Peale, offering portraits by C.W.Peale. For letter, see: A.R. Peale to T.L. Montgomery; Jan. 17, 1929.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, May 6, 1929; 7x6; Alsop, Jessie M.
    Middletown, Conn., A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Asks for information on a Rembrandt Peale portrait.
  - Letter to Miss Jessie M. Alsop, Middletown, Conn., May 16, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning her portrait by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to H[orace] W. Sellers, Philadelphia, May 19, 1929; 6-1/2x8-1/2; Alsop, Jessie M.
    Middletown, Conn., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning her portrait by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Jessie M. Alsop, Middletown, Conn., June 1, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Comments on her portrait by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to H[orace] W. Sellers, Philadelphia, June 3, 1929; 7x6; Alsop, Jessie M.
    Middletown, Conn.; Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Cannot place a value on the Rembrandt Peale portrait.
  - Letter to Miss Jessie M. Alsop, Middletown, Conn., June 6, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning the value of Rembrandt Peale's portraits.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, March 25, 1930; 7-1/2x5; Stretch, Caroline Wood
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Must sell her Rembrandt Peale minatures
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, April 1, 1930; 7-1/2x5; Stretch, Carolyn Wood
    A.L.S. 4p.and Photo.of clock-face. (see Peale papers.) Concerning the minetures she purchased as by Rembrandt Peale, although they may be by James Peale. Her clock, "the oldest in America."
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, Nov. 25, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Cret, Paul Philippe, 1876-1945
    Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Gives the name of a Frenchman who may have data on Rembrandt Peale's visit in France.
  - Letter to Paul Philippe Cret, Philadelphia, Nov. 29, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Rembrandt Peale's visit to France and C.W.Peale's attitude to the French.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, Dec. 20, 1932; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Réau, Louis, 1881-1961
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Wants information on Rembrandt Peale while in France, for he wishes to revive Rembrandt Peale in France. Refers to their friend, P.P.Cret.
  - Letter to Louis Réau, Paris, France, Feb. 27, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Rembrandt Peale's French portraits.
  - Letter to [Horace W.] Sellers, March 18, 1933; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Réau, Louis, 1881-1961
    Paris, France, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale Papers.) Needs photographs of portrais of French men done by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Paul P. Cret, Philadelphia, March 20, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning information for Mr. Réau on Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Horace Wells Sellers, Philadelphia, March 23, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Cret, Paul Philippe, 1876-1945
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning requests of M. Réau.
  - Letter to Paul P. Cret, Philadelphia, March 30, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Charles Willson Peale, Rembrandt Peale's portraits of Frenchmen for Louis Réau.
  - Letter to Louis Réau, Paris, France, April 4, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Horace Wells, 1857-1933
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Rembrandt Peale's portraits done in France.
  - Note to Tracy's Book Store, New London, Conn., June 9, 1936; 3-1/4x5-1/2; Wormser, Richard S.(Richard Samuel), 1898-1975
    New York, N. 1p.on postal card. (see Peale papers.) Selections from sale of Rembrandt Peale's effects.
  - Letter to Charles C. Sellers, Nov. 18, 1937; 6-1/2x5; Zandt, Anne B.
    Hamilton Square, N.J., A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning minatures painted by some Peales.
  - Letter to [Leslie Clarence] Dunn, Jan. 5, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Castle, William E. (William Ernest), 1867-1962
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 2p. (see Castle papers.) Describes their home in California. Needs yellow mice for genetic experiment.
  - Correspondence with Hal Durrell, March-April, 1938; Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-1980
    Includes photographic prints and negatives.
  - Letter to Charles [C.] Sellers, New London, Conn., April 25, 1939; 10x6-3/4; Fitz-Gibbon, Ethel
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning a painting by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Charles [c.] Sellers, Feb. 29, 1940; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Holden, Edith
    Hebron, Conn.; Greenwich, Conn., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Questions concerning possible Rembrandt Peale portraits.
  - Letter to [Charles C. Sellers], Sept. 14, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Merritt, Jesse, 1889-1957
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Asks for information on portrait by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Charles C. Sellers, Hebron, Conn, March 6, 1942; 7-1/4x8-1/2; Driscoll, George M.
    Sag Harbor, N.Y., A.L.S. 5p. (see Peale papers.) Asks for help in identifying a pope, painted by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to [Charles Coleman] Sellers, March 20, 1942; 7-1/4x8-1/2; Driscoll, George M.
    Sag Harbor, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning the portrait of a pope by Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to "Mattie" [Martha S. Grubb], July 2, 1942; 5x3-1/2; Morris, Anna Wharton, 1868-1957
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Thinks she should give the Peale item to C.C.Sellers.
  - Letter to Charles Coleman Sellers, Hebron, Conn., July 8, 1942; 7x6; Grubb, Martha S.
    Bryn Mawr, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.and envelope: registered mail. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Sends Peale letter. Wishes to read his book.
  - Letter to Charles Coleman Sellers, Jan. 21, 1946; 11x8-1/2; Cunningham, Charles Crehore, 1910-1979
    Middletown, Conn.; Hartford, Conn., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning a self-portrait by Rembrandt peale.
  - Letter to Francis Harper, Swarthmore, Penna., June 4, 1946; 11x8-1/2; Palmer, Ralph S. (Ralph Simon), 1914-2003
    Poughkeepsie, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale Papers.) Concerning paintings by T.R.Peale in Maine.
  - Letter to Charles C. Sellers, Middletown, Conn., July 17, 1946; 11x8-1/2; Palmer, Ralph S. (Ralph Simon), 1914-2003
    Old Town, Maine, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Comments on the T.R.Peale item on Maine.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Clara Robbins], Oct. 23, 1946; 8x5; Johnson, Mary A. Peale
    Los Angeles, Cal., A.L.S. 12p. (see Peale Papers) Concerning the Pen Women. Concerning the APS Hall and C.W.Peale and his family (some of which in incorrect). Her antiques. Refers to a Jefferson signature.
    Presented by Dr. and Mrs. W. J. Robbins, June 1963.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Clara Robbins], April 8, 1947; 8x5; Johnson, Mary A. Peale
    Los Angeles, Cal., A.L.S. 5p. (see Peale papers.) Offer to her of underwriting a publication on C.W.Peale and his being placed in the Hall of Fame. Asks if she should do such a thing.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Clara Robbins;], Aug.? 24, 1952; 8-1/4x6; Johnson, Mary A. Peale
    A.L. 4p. (see Peale papers) Family news. Friendly letter.
    Presented by Dr. and Mrs. W. J. Robbins, June 1963. Presented by Dr. and Mrs. W. J. Robbins, June 1963.
  - Letter to Charles Coleman Sellers, Carlisle, Penna., March 5, 1953; 11x8-1/2; Stern, Max, 1903-1980
    Montreal, Canada, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Asks him if he could identify a portrait, which may be by one of the Peales.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Clara Robbins], April 21, 1954; 8-1/4x6; Johnson, Mary A. Peale
    Los Angeles, Cal., A.L.S. 6p. (see Peale papers.) Friendly, newsy letter of her family and life.
  - Letter to "Dear Florence", Feb. 27, 1960; 9x6; Peale, Robert R.
    Denver, Col., A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning Clara Robbins, Buffalo Bill Cody, etc. His painting of G.Washington.
  - Letter to Robert Ridgway Peale, Denver Col., June 28, 1960; 8-1/4x6; Robbins, Clara Fedderhoff (Box 25)
    Bronxville, N.Y., A.L.S. 4p.and envelope. (see Peale papers.) Asks for information pertaining to C.W.Peale for the APS as her son, W.J. Robbins requested. The first "Wild West" show in Nebraska. Wants portrait done of her son, W.J.Robbins.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers., Undated; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Adams, G. Howe (Box 26)
    A.L.S. 8p. Concerning right-handed and lefthanded people. Concerning Dr. Agnew.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] C. Sellers, Undated; 10x8; Anthony, John Gould, 1804-1877
    A.L.S. 2p.and end. In pencil. (see Peale papers.) Botany. Feb. 22
  - Letter to Mrs. [Elizabeth Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Ashbridge, Mary Kenyon
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. Vol Ip.75
  - Letter to Mrs. N. [Elizabeth Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 8x6-1/2; Ashbridge, Mary Kenyon
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. vol I p.75.
    The following was a note on the leaf to which this item was pasted: "Mary Kenyon sister of Capt. Heny Kenyon were friends of Nathan Sellers and Elizabeth his wife but not related. The intimacy possibly led to her calling Elizabeth Sellers 'mother'."
  - Letter to [Horace W] Sellers, Undated; 6x5; Atkinson, Louisa?
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning pictures by C.W. and Rembrandt Peale. July 24
  - Letter to Ella P[eale] Sellers, Cincinnati, Ohio, Undated; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Aylmer, Gerald George
    D. Valentine. 1p.and envelope. (see Peale papers.) Feb. 14
  - Letter to Adaline E. Hodges, Alexandria, Va., Undated; 5x4; Bradford, Julius, b. 1829
    Wilmington, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale papers.) love letter. Nov. 28
  - Letter to Mr. Peale., Undated; 6-1/4x8; Burke, Edward
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale papers.) Asks how the duck could be killed.
  - Letter to [Eleanor S Peale?], Undated; Charlotte
    May 11
  - Letter to Ann Sellers., Undated; 8-1/4x7-3/4; Coleman, Ann Bettle
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. In pencil. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [George] E[scol] Sellers, Undated; 8x5; Corwin, Thomas, 1794-1865
    Thursday. A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale papers.) Asks him to attend to business for them
  - Letter to Geo[rge] E. Sellers., Undated; 8x5; Corwin, Thomas, 1794-1865
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale Papers.) Will see him tonight since he goes to court today.
  - Letter to Mrs. Amies, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Crammer, E. Z.
    Wheeling, West Va., A.L.S. 3p. (see Peale papers.) Sorry Miss Margaret died, but knows it is for the best. Family news. March 5
  - Letter to Miss Anna Peale., Undated; 10x8; Darley, Felix Octavius Carr, 1822-1888
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Illustrated poem. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Love letter.
  - Letter to Anna Peale., Undated; 10-1/4x7-3/4; Darley, Felix Octavius Carr, 1822-1888
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. Illustrated. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Hopes he hasnot offended her.
  - Letter to Charles Wil[l]son Peale, Philadelphia, Undated; 8x6-1/2; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    [mailed,] A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards clothes. Aug. 17
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Undated; 12-3/4x7-3/4; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 1p.and add. Fragment. Concerning the De Peyster family.
  - Letter to Mr. Sellers, Undated; 9x7-1/2; Dickinson, John, 1732-1808
    London, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale papers.) Business. Nov. 10
  - Letter to [James Peale], Undated; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Duncan, Anna Claypoole Peale Staughton, 1791-1878
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a wedding. vol VIIp.62. Oct. 6
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 6x4-1/4; Fassitt, F. T. (Francis T.)
    This was located originally in: Coleman Sellers, and old photographic club.
    A.L.S. 1p.and enc.of 2 photographs. (see Peale papers.) Sends prints of pictures as requested. Jan. 13
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 8x4-3/4; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Tuesday. A.L.S.with initials. 4p. Concerning the engraver, Fick. He is writing on paper made originally for Stephen Girard.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 8x5; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 1p. Will see him Wednesday.
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, Undated; 7x4; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Friday. A.L.S. 4p. Concerning sealing wax.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Gillespie, E. D. (Elizabeth Duane), b. 1821
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Asks that he be at a meeting to receive the "aids of the 'Calico Teap-Party'". Dec. 8.
  - Letter to Lin[n]aeus Peale, Philadelphia, Undated; 10x8; Godman, Angelica Peale, 1800-1859
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 64. April 24
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Undated; 8x5; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asks for his clothes and will send others to the museum tomorrow. vol VIIp.61. March 8
  - Letter to Mrs. E[lizabeth Coleman] Sellers, Upper Darby, Undated; 10x8; Grant, Catharine, d.1834
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. vol IIp.22. March 30
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers]., Undated; 8x5; Grimmer, Louisa Peale
    A.L.S.: Lui. 2p. (see Peale papers.) Concerning possible burial of G.E.Sellers.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Philadelphia, Undated; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Grubb, Martha G.
    Danbury, A.L.S.with initials. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. vol I.p.85. Sept. 5
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Undated; 8x5; Grubb, Martha G.
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning a visit to C.W.Peale's.